DURGA PRASAD PALLI

Head of Digital Marketing

Jubilee Hills, Hyderabad Mobile: 9441031224

Email Id: palliprasad999@gmail.com

PROFILE

Creative & knowledgeable Digital Marketing Manager with an extensive experience in developing data-driven marketing campaigns & strategies, successfully managing DM teams, and monitoring performance of the campaigns. Exceptional management professional with excellent communication/leadership skills & strong attention detail.

SKILLS

Technical: Search Engine Optimization, Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Google Ads, Social Media Ads - Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, YouTube & LinkedIn

Non Technical: Team Management, Client Interaction, Reporting, MS Office & many more....

EXPERIENCE

Pencap Technologies Pvt Ltd, Banjara Hills - Head of Digital Marketing

November 2017 - PRESENT

- Handling a team of 7-10 Digital Marketing Team to run performance driven & brand awareness campaigns
- Planning & executing strategies through display & search platforms after receiving new briefs from the clients
- Communicating and proposing channels to clients on media planning strategies and setting campaigns KPIs
- Created, monitored and optimized campaigns on digital platforms such as Google Ads,
 Facebook & Instagram Ads etc
- Reviewed the performance of all campaigns; Built report template for monitoring the performance on daily basis for always on campaign and initiated interim reporting for tactical campaigns
- Meeting with clients on a regular basis to acquired insight in online marketing trends to ensure that the marketing strategies are up-to-date
- Worked closely with the internal teams such as UI, UX Team, Graphic Designing & Video Team to achieve performance objectives
- Being a manager, I've involved in many of the company decisions & building the portfolios

Digital Marketing Consulting India, Hyderabad - Intern

July 2017 - August 2017

- Completed Internship in SEO, SEM, Facebook, LinkedIn, Google, Twitter Marketing
 Created a website and hosted in server
- Linked website to Google Analytics & Search Console
- SEO On-Page & OFF-Page Optimization
- Created Facebook, LinkedIn Pages
- Executed Google AdWords, Facebook Page Likes, LinkedIn Post Likes campaign successfully
- Certified Google AdWords Fundamental & Search Advertising

TWINIX INFOMEDIA PVT. LTD, Hyderabad - Web Analyst

December 2015 - January 2017

Project: Reachflare.com (Outreach Marketing)

Skills: Microsoft Excel, Research, Analysis, Data Scraping Tools, SEO Metrics Tools, Competitor Analysis Tools, Team Management

- Gathered 50K list of publishers/bloggers and reviewed their sites, Reviewing Includes collecting their average monthly traffic, domain authority, site niche & various site metrics
- Used different tools to identify, collect and review bloggers email
- Maintained databases in Excel and used different excel functions to avoid replication of data
- Assigned Email campaigns daily for both publishers and agencies/advertisers
- Filtered the cold emails, inbound emails and moved the emails into Pipelines

Project: Customerservicedirectory.com (Information Site)

Skills: Google Analytics, Word press, Microsoft Excel, Image Compressors, Content Research, Team Management

- This is an information site where are all the international brands (which covers around 1000 brands) customer care numbers, toll-free numbers, service centres, dealer locations and branch offices for respective countries
- Downloaded the Analytics of the site from Google Analytics for the past one year
- Analysed the site traffic, page visitors and bounce rate
- Deleted and redirected the pages which are not performing well and getting maximum bounce rate
- Added content to the pages (around 300 pages) which are performing less number of visitors, and succeeded in increasing the number of visitors to the pages

Project: Customercareinfo.in (Information Site)

- This site is getting around 2lakhs unique visitors per month
- By using Google Analytics deleted some pages and redirected as per the less number of page views and bounce rate
- Added content for 120 posts like customer care, service centres, dealer locations etc., for the pages having less number of views and content

Additional Skills: Google Analytics, Google AdWords, Search Console, Social Media, Facebook Marketing, LinkedIn Marketing, Keyword Research, Team Management, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, Budgeting, Negotiating etc.,

EDUCATION

Gudlavalleru Engineering College, Gudlavalleru - B.Tech

October 2010 - June 2014

Agg: 59%

P.R.S.M National Junior College, Vuyyuru- MPC

July 2008 - June 2010

Agg: 80.5%

Santiniketan English Medium School, Vuyyuru- SSC

Agg: 63.5%

PERSONAL PROFILE

Father Name: Lakshmana Rao Palli Mother Name: Vijaya Lakshmi Palli

Strengths: Patience, Self-Motivated, Honesty, Sincerity

Marital Status: Married

Languages Known: English, Telugu, Hindi

Gender: Male

Interests: Internet Surfing, Watching Movies

Nationality: Indian

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/durga-prasad-palli/